[Music]
you're listening to the AI native Dev
brought to you by
[Applause]
[Music]
Tesla hello and welcome again to a
another monthly episode our second
monthly episode second we're getting
getting to be Pros here or rather
recurring we're getting into a rhythm so
this month we're getting more into our
normal Cadence of weekly episode and
we're actually going one week each so
myself doing one and then yourself so we
did four this month excluding of course
the monthly which we released shortly as
as learning the right pace yeah so we
started off with isma from codium Ai and
talked about AI testing then we moved on
to the wonderful James Ward A friend of
mine from many years back from the
ancient worlds of of java from the
ancient and existing of java James just
moving over to AWS actually from Google
in very interesting role as a Dev
advocate in the world of AI and Q
developer from Amazon and we also talked
about Jason War a wonderful episode with
yourself and Jason very super
interesting stuff yeah digging into Cod
generation models and more yeah of
course Jason previously CTO of GitHub
now CEO of poolside and Bala nigh house
really interesting Hands-On episode
about how we can use tdd to generate
code from our own test which we write
and this lovely little iterative Loop
that he created as a tool to build
effectively components from tests yeah
so and I love that episode very much
came from him sharing his work not
anything around broader maybe this sort
of the previous establishment of some
credentials to maybe you have something
smart in this space he's actually built
a thing he presented about it caught our
attention and we reached out to uh to
talk to him very very interesting it was
it was very conference driven
development that one actually because he
was just talking about I can't remember
what the topic was he was talking about
something and someone said why can't we
do it the other way around why can't you
get code rather than generate tests
about your code which where we were
talking with codium the other way around
what about if your code was generated
from your test and you thought oh it's
an interesting project yeah let's go
away and do it and so that's how yeah
conference driven development I love it
all about the feedback yeah so let's
talk about some topics then one one
which I know would very much interested
you was the idea of how
llms have a greater capacity or or
sometimes find it easier to effectively
understand more than generate and then
sometimes generate is easier than
understanding I know Jason had very good
insights into this as well and sometimes
maybe differ from others that from those
of it Tomar so first of all I think it's
a it's interesting to to set the stage
around what is sort of the problem or
what is the the different perspectives
you might have which is one assumes that
the complicated thing when you talk
about generating anything about code
generating docks generating tests
generating new code to add into that
system system that the complicated piece
is understanding the code and itar was
very very crisp about saying I think the
hardest thing is to know what to test
for is to understand the code to
understand what are correct and
incorrect systems within it and it's not
all the knowledge about what test for
sits in the in the code itself so maybe
it's a bit more than that but that's the
hardest thing and then it's not that
it's trivial to generate tests but that
is the easier part once you know what
you're testing for so that was
interesting and it it drove I think
we'll touch on that a but it drove them
to actually create you know more tools
that revolved around whatever it is that
they understood in there and
incidentally actually on that I remember
one of the early sessions that we did
with rashab from sourc the makers of
Cody they he also mentioned when you
think about the human interaction that
if you've got 200 tests there's a
certain area of code that you want the
human to focus on and it's almost like
helping the AI to understand what to
test not not the fact that it's created
so many but the areas I need to focus on
most so it's an interesting kind of Del
between Windows and I think there's
something uh sensible about this right
if you think about what it means to be a
good developer you think about the
effort of writing tests today there's an
effort in whatever writing down the
lines of code definitely in maintaining
those that's a different story uh but
the real kind of tough questions is do
you know what type of tests do you want
to run then yeah you need to not be lazy
and actually write those down so it's
interesting just that that difference
between understanding what a test for
and and with it understanding the code
and then generation and and I think itar
was sort of implying that's the
complexity and the hard thing that
they're dealing with which again is not
just understanding the code but is about
identifying what they do and Jason's
view seems to have been that the llms
are actually further along down the
route of understanding code than they
are generation first of all he also
unsolicited pointed out this dichotomy
and interesting to to just think about
this as two things understanding the
code and creating it and it's it's not
surprising a lot of the sort of startups
in the domain of AI code generation are
priding themselves guess around the
their ability to index an Enterprise
code but but also understanding the code
and then generating it but I guess the
perspective that I understood from Jason
is that the llms as they stand today are
actually much better because I asked him
about what are the edges right now of
capabilities and he felt like
understanding code is actually something
LMS are a lot better at today and that
the generation part of it is maybe the
part that they're still working on
they're still evolving and he was
pointing out that these LMS are not yet
Junior developers and again we can talk
a little bit more about sort of the
evolution of the individual so I guess
what I found interesting in the
observation is just first of all uh uh
coming back to understanding that when
you talk about whether something works
or it doesn't work there seems to be a
focus on did it not work because it
didn't understand your context it didn't
understand your existing code base last
time we talked about how that context
might be bad had there's a lot that you
might not want it to mimic in your
context but it needs to understand what
the context was and then the other part
is the Gen part of the geni and maybe
the piece that I talked to uh itamar
about is this notion that it's called
gen and we think a lot we lean into the
generative but actually still the
interpretation still the sort of the
analytical part of AI but using still
the same llms and their Innovations have
driven maybe how much of the value I
guess that we're recuring right now
comes from that yeah yeah and it's
interesting actually because when we go
back to the session that we had with
Amir shabat we were talking a lot about
the categorization and I think on the
last monthly you mentioned about how we
kind of initially started off with all
these categories of tools and then when
we talked to the vendors of course
vendors are doing multiple things I know
this is something that you have thought
a lot about in terms of when we think
about the
commoditization effectively of that
understanding of that code search the
additional aspects to actually provide
the value to the user whether it's
testing or whether it's something else
it's actually probably a smaller step
and actually becomes a a more unique
part for that tool so there's there's
less of a jump to to to get a testing
tool or documentation tool and so forth
from that what are your thoughts in
terms of the the the the tooling
ecosystem going forward if that becomes
commoditized and how will that change
how tools are produced I think that's
really the eventual conclusion from this
there's two theories that you might
embrace one is is that the hardest part
is understanding the code and that
becomes the center of gravity and that a
few big platforms become really good at
understanding your code and because they
really get it they understand the code
they understand what's right about it
why how it works they are able to
produce a bunch of these surrounding
functionalities like generating test
generating documentation generating new
code within that surrounding resolving
bugs because they get it they understand
your code they understand your context
very well and so that theory of how the
Market might evolve leads into more of
like single platforms that as a company
maybe you would really centralize on I'm
going to use this platform and I would
going to use its set of tools because it
really understands my code that's one
path the second path assumes that
understanding your code while very
important will get commoditized that the
llms will just understand it or there
will be some diminishing return paths or
approaches to to improve it to get
better at understanding your code and so
everybody would do it at around the same
level and without much effort so you
just pointed to my codebase and I'll
understand it and from there that leads
it more to best of breed tools now it's
okay if you already everybody
understands the code and it's not hard
to get the tool to understand it now you
really want to say I want my testing
tool to really get testing I want it to
understand maybe my product analytics
and I want it to understand real world
traffic that flows through my system and
I would like it to understand my
business case and what is important to
me my documentation tool maybe relates
to how I disseminate that and which
platforms are using it and how do I
integrate and similarly for code
generation or bug resolution of those
those maybe it's related to what's my
platform maybe what's doing it more
secure so each of these different tools
might bring its own uh specialization
and so that's more of a best of breed
tool and they both they revolve really
around what's your perspective around
how hard both from an IP perspective and
from an implementation perspective would
it be to understand your code and how
much is that eventually the deciding
factor yeah because I guess if it's not
and it does get commoditized like you
say into a model let say it puts
everyone on a much more Level Playing
Field and then I guess it comes down to
again that Dev stickiness the ux as our
Dev tooling aicardo guy from I think
you've had what 50 successful startups
now in the dental space yeah I've met
with
50 you've invested in
50 it's again down to whatever the dev
favorite tool is not about the
capability of the tool per se but about
how easy it is to use and potentially it
comes down to consolidation again with
the one tool that can do enough of it
well enough and it's very easy to for me
to use in my workflow it it it very
often wins yeah and I think I would like
the second theory that assumes that the
understanding of the code would either
prove not as critical or be sufficiently
commoditized because I think that leads
to a more thriving ecosystem right if
you create if you assume that there's
going to be one like deeply
understanding platform that gets your
code and therefore it would have all the
cards then it doesn't lead to
competition it doesn't lead to
Innovation versus if you assume that
everybody can do that everybody can
understand everybody's probably an
exaggeration fine not everybody you need
some level of Competency and
investment but once you've built that
understanding of the code then you can
build these things now each of these
tools can specialize and can optimize
they might optimize indeed on E of use
they might optimize on uh specific
ecosystems and verticals they might
optimize on maybe a new stack that that
comes along maybe it's just opinion
there are different ways to document
they different they're sometimes opposed
so if you subscribe to if you prefer if
your taste if your preference is more on
one route you'll choose that tool great
example being Q developer which yes it's
a generic code completion actually other
things as well coding assistant there it
has a quite a specialization around the
Amazon the AWS Services base so if you
wanted to code against an Amazon AWS API
y it's very good at actually attaching
to existing services and things like
that so those kind of specializations
where if you're developing an Amazon
stack your mileage will will go much
further yeah and and I think that's a
good example I think in general anything
that's within an ecosystem might
specialize because people would have
invested in that while if you're sort of
imagining a place in which it's so hard
to understand the code and that's
important or critical to the success
then yeah maybe there's a few companies
that are happy about it if they are the
ones that have won but then it means
probably companies pick one and maybe
eventually they have more but mostly
they try to concentrate on one and that
means a new vendor has to plug into it
build on their understanding so there
are it's not all Gloom if it is about
that sort of central element then what
you'd expect is you expect those that
make available or are able to produce
that understanding of the code to become
a platform and allow others to connect
but I I guess my my my hope is that it's
less about this holistic understanding
of the code but also also I think that's
my expectation I don't know sort of
looking at the code and maybe it's
aligned with what Jason was saying which
is he feels
the systems understand the code pretty
well he's building a foundation model so
maybe he's okay my Foundation model will
just understand it as is so there's like
different levels of platform here but
but I also I guess I I expect that
because I don't know I don't know what
your opinion is like I feel I I always
equate it to human understanding and I
think there's a level of understanding
of your code that is sufficient that at
that point if you want to write docs if
you want to write tests if you want to
write all these other things then okay
you have enough understanding of the
code from here on Bud your competency in
that yeah yeah absolutely leads us
nicely on actually we talked about this
a few times prior to this month but came
up a number of times during the sessions
this month which is really about what a
future developer will look like and I
think there's a couple of pieces here
one talking about the role of a
developer today and how I guess AI is
currently impacting on that or assisting
that role today and perhaps even an
overestimation of its capability today
which we'll talk about that in a second
and then second secondly in future how
do we expect AI to change our jobs and
in what capacity maybe we start with
Jason first because he talked a little
bit about the impact of AI on our
behaviors today and this notion many
people have battered about which is it
it is as good as a junior developer
today yeah now his opinion of course was
yeah that it's not at all yeah I think
the quote was something like none of
these are junior developers yeah the
quote was AI assistant are evolving but
there's still a leap to make before we
even start thinking about them as
autonomous Junior developers and there's
a lot of talk about hands on keyboard
and the need for developers to still
have hands on keyboard because it's just
not there it's not there in that fully
automated sense I find all this quite
fascinating first of all it's an
observation that is about the current
state of-the-art in terms of the
technology and in his defense he was
referring to to his own platform as well
so he says like it's not like the models
Just Produce Junior developers out of
the blue I like use the word autonomous
there last time we geeked out a little
bit about about the term autonomy I
talked to Des at intercom about that and
autonomy probably is around just sort of
the it's a it's a size question so there
are some can you autonomously summarize
an email for me they can do that today
but you don't call that autonomous
because it's too small the task is too
small so I guess there's a little bit of
lack of clarity about what is a junior
developer what is the scope of a task
that a junior developer can do that is
enough to give it that sort of title
autonomy right but but I think it's I I
thought there was really interesting
around first of all it led to a bunch of
this conversation around understanding
the codes as well he implied I don't
think he said that explicitly that it it
would be better able to explain the code
to you at a relatively senior level than
be able to execute it and I think really
a lot of that boils down to autonomy
right and if if you think about this in
the context of what is a what is the
future of a of a developer I think it's
interesting and I guess he was still
leaning to in the next few years we're
still thinking about primarily AI as
assistants and the developer engaging
with them which I think is is like a
little bit unexciting but maybe it's a
transitionary period I don't know how
much do like reviewing tests and and
code that got generated it's going to
become like the code reviews right where
if it's a if it's a few lines then maybe
I'll look at it if it's a 500 line maybe
I'll scan it and have no comments about
it and just accept it and I think it's a
little bit it's a bit of a a bummer
thought to think that we will get stuck
in this mode fine co-pilot po side
whatever all these things they're going
to generate code for us and then we will
we will review that and we would have
written it faster fine maybe we're
faster but as long as it's not
autonomous in the sense that we can
trust it then basically our job becomes
reviewers and that's not a fun job and
and that's the key isn't it it's trust
it's trust in the ability to say I'm
accepting what you are what you're
providing me and that's not through my
blind Trust of your ability to create
code it's through testing and assertions
that are passing based on that but once
you are able to trust you're not
reviewing so much anymore or it's not in
the usual workflow to dip into the code
and start looking at that Jason
mentioned two parts product and
architect now we've battered around
architect a little bit in the past as
well as the future of development I
think that resonates with you as well
quite it does yeah absolutely so I think
once you get past the hope that the
future of a software developer is not a
code reviewer I don't think we want that
and so because we don't want that I
don't think it'll stay there and let's
assume from an autonom perspective we
will have gained enough trust to to give
it that title of autonomy then okay what
does a developer do and I really liked
how Jason phrased it quite aligned to
how I think which is on one side you
might have some developers that lean
product they lean user needs they lean
an understanding of what is it that the
software should be able to provide to
the user to address the problem and so I
think that's one path it's probably a
bit more well understood right now and
some developers love that and some do
not and so if if you're a developer that
more leans into into the technical
aspects I'm drawn into software
development because of the problem
solving aspects to it then you might go
more down an architect route and the
architect route is interesting because
Architects actually don't touch code
much I don't know like I I'm at this
point overhead and quite Rusty and so
hard for me to comment on what I do
today but as I was more in architect
roles I understood code I cared about
code I could look about code I could
understand the implications of code my
job wasn't n really about writing code
also the more and I think we discussed
this the more towards architecture you
go the more kind of naturally polyglot
you become and he linked into that and
he talked about all sorts of aeric
languages and generating them I think
it's interesting is these two paths if
you were drawn into software development
because of the creation element because
you want to solve problems and it's
exciting to you that you can write some
code and suddenly you can have a system
that does X you might move up the
product manager route which certain
developers do today and if you're drawn
into software development more because
of the problem solving then you might
move up this architect route that is
more
about solving problems at a slightly
higher resolution with code being a
solved problem just as as we did today
with abstractions in languages send a
request over the network and you don't
feel like you are solving a lesser
problem because you don't need to
actually write the btes and the bits on
the on the wire yeah and I think there
are two other points of view here which
are well worth mentioning first of all
the testing point of view and secondly
the kind of more of the role where we
think about it from a larger spec space
the testing point of view is interesting
because it kind of was really focusing
on the code no longer being the most
important artifact that a developer
would work on and this is really
something that would help gather that
trust of generated code and an
interesting quote here from Bala he said
developers are increasingly test writers
and one of the things that was leaning
into is the fact that if develop velers
are focused more on tests and the tests
are creating a specification as to what
the application should look like and and
then the application can be
generated number one the tests are the
most important artifact in that because
that's your source of uh truth and yeah
number two you don't even need to look
at the code because if your tests are
good and the tests pass you don't care
how it's implemented almost and in our
session there's in fact I fell in the
Trap of oh can you show me the code I'd
love to see the implementation and B was
like no you don't need to look at the
code and it it was an interesting
conversation just works yeah and it's
more kind of habit to say I want to see
the code I'm curious as how it's done
that so that was one piece an
interesting piece and the second piece
was itar and and when you were talking
the future he was talking about it being
PRD and specification and from that the
test can be generated directly from that
specification and that kind of leans
very much into the AI native Viewpoint
of having the specification and things
being pulled from that specification
very different style of development
which we're used to today yeah
absolutely and I think
there's different things that pull at
this future role of a developer uh one
aspect of it is what would the uh tools
make available right what can they do
and therefore what is the job that is
left to be done and so if tools are able
to write code and they're able to write
codes to a level that you trust then you
have to start thinking about okay what's
my job it doesn't matter what I I like
doing or what I don't like doing what is
needed of me I think I'd like to think
that writing tests literally is just
like hey this is just the uh the outcome
of the validation for most people is
really no more fun than reviewing code
and so I think it is very functional
it's a way for us to to drive I think
the move towards PRD and specs and those
terminologies similar to the statement
of Architects also touches on what could
be the next craft because I don't think
you're going to get a lot of 18y olds
signing up to University to become test
writers or code reviewers but would they
sign up to be product requirements
writers so your problem solving is on
the user base or would they sign up to
become Architects I think those are are
real paths I think we're combining this
today to be able to achieve value from
the llms you need to either allow them
to write the code and then review it
because you don't trust them yet and do
that less and less or you need to
provide tests that give you confidence
in both cases what you're doing is
you're verifying their work and I think
really we're going to evolve into a
place which it's a more collaborative
mode in which you are trusting that they
will do this piece and therefore you are
doing something that is more high level
yeah another good Jason quote I wish I
was 25 years old again the next 20 years
would be totally different two questions
guy question one do you remember being
25 years old and question two it's
actually really hard to to be someone
just coming into the space right now as
a developer whether through University
or just being 25 and trying to make your
way because you can't can't see where
you're going to be in two three four
five years if AI does take over this
space but secondly it was a it was at
least a little bit clear in terms of
your trajectory your path having the
idea of product in the architect side
it's lovely to to be able to view that
path what kind of advice would you give
to people starting off now is it
something they should be frightened
about something they can get ahead in
it's really tough right it's I think the
the factual part I think in Jason's
quote there is is the next 20 years will
have been very different I think that's
really hard to contest yeah if you start
coding today or if you're 25 maybe
you're a few years into that coding then
your next 20 years are different than if
you did that 20 years ago or whatever
100 years ago like myself and but I
think whether you wish the first part of
like I wish I was I think that's a bit
debatable it's hard to really say what
is the advice to build in I think
there's the life advice which is you
invest in in resilience and and be
adaptable and learn to learn and be able
to adjust but I think also a lot of the
core principles are similar to maybe
guidance that you would give people
around being too enamored with a single
language and sort of say really again
when you're senior enough developers I
don't care I initially learned to
program in Pascal back in the Dark Ages
and then I learned C and C++ and then
Java and then net and then Java script
and it's okay like it's all programming
it's all development they're all tools
to a means and so it's maybe just
leaning into what is making you tick and
think about code not as an identity but
rather as tools of the craft yeah
absolutely I think that's really good
advice we talked about the code not
looking at the code and let's I'll
mention a couple of quotes and then
we'll talk about Jason love that
provocation right yeah why do you need
to look at the code and it's it is
against what we as developers want to do
right as as soon as people see see a
product I want to see the code I want to
see the code so James said I'm wondering
why does that code actually need to
exist in a human readable form if the AI
can actually get it right if the AI has
some form or way to express what I'm
trying to get to then why does the code
need to be readable Bala also said you
wouldn't need to look at the code if the
tests are good enough you have to trust
the generated code from from the AI the
tests are actually what become Paramount
and now Jason a hard time ingesting that
kind of viewpoint he still thinks there
are experts that will need to understand
the code your thoughts yeah and I think
he even phrased it a little bit is it's
hard for me to foresee that that you
wouldn't need to know code at all again
two interpretations that might be here
one which I think is right is we're
having some separation anxiety here and
I think it's absolutely right that if we
get to that trust and that if is
probably a word to lean in if we get to
that trust that whatever higher level
representation we have is is trustworthy
that it would create something that that
actually provides that writes the code
behind the scenes or does whatever it is
that it wants to do to provide us with a
functionality that we requested then why
do we need to look at the code at the
same time a lot of developers today they
perceive themselves as coders a lot of
the world of software development of
Open Source they are all about the
source they're about the code and people
take pride in their
crafts I think the world of creation has
seen this for instance with the move to
digital and it probably still is the
case where a lot of people feel that
drawing with brushes and and paints is
not the same as drawing digitally and
some people feel the opposite and some
people feel that you know playing an
instrument that is actually producing
vocally The Sounds is very different
than is the true Music Creation versus
anything digital let alone EDM or
electronic sort of sampling so I think
it's a new mode of creation and I think
it'll take a while I do want to point
out that we still have Mainframe
developers out there they're paid very
well because technology doesn't die and
it sticks around and someone needs to
maintain it but it's hard for me to
imagine how a Cutting Edge developer in
five years time not alone 10 is really
coding much if anything at all yeah very
interesting and of course models will
improve over time to to match that
reality one of the things Jason
obviously at poolside creating looking
at creating a specific geni model around
coding and there's a lot of talk around
specific models versus generic models
and which will win which are needed and
yeah great quote which Jason also said
was in a world with infinite resources
the general purpose model is key to AGI
but in reality we Face constraints on
energy data time how do we balance these
limits so what are your thoughts in
terms of whether generic models will get
to that stage where they're going to be
good enough for coding versus specific
models that are trained for that very
purpose are going to be a league ahead
of those generic models that is the mul
billion dollar question based on of the
amount of venture investment right now
in in Foundation
model I thought that perspective was
very interesting and very valuable and I
don't know like maybe I'm too much of a
reductionist here but I like trying to
find the primary pivot Points in a bunch
of these decisions and I think the key
one here is around scaling if you
believe that we are uh going to be able
to continue to feed these these training
processes more and more data and
continue to see as we have that if you
give them large volumes of data large
volumes of compute and if you do
substantially more than that then you
will get substantially better results
then I think that diminishes the the
value of dedicated models like pide like
robotics models to an extent even itar
talked about their sort of test specific
models although I'm not sure how those
are built we didn't talk as much about
that and if you're going to there on the
other hand if you think and there's some
rumors around that that we're actually
at a bit of a local Maxima in terms of
our ability to train and that the gp5
and equivalent models will actually have
a hard time and they will become more
like 4.1 4.2 and it'll take us a bunch
of years two three four years to figure
out how to make some advancement maybe
power is indeed the opposal maybe
something else and so we resort to
algorithmic uh changes things like that
then it actually is easy to believe that
if you took a code only model and you
basically uh picked amidst the huge
volumes of data the subset of data that
is relevant to coding however like you
need to be good at that then maybe you
produce something that is a lot better
because it's purpose built and doing the
same for different domains so yeah I
think it's really interesting and I
guess as a consumer uh I'm happy that
there's enough Venture money you know
kind ofing around to try these different
paths there are environmental aspects to
it which are not negligible yeah which
is not awesome as a as an investor those
are very hard decisions to make and I
guess they're still being made because
if they do prove correct there are very
big uh uh amounts to be won so I think
as developers as tool builders on top of
llms I think it's yet another reason to
believe that the llms will continue to
get better and better a generating code
because we have very capable very
well-funded companies trying both paths
and others yeah yeah super interesting
it' be interesting to see how that
changes over the years so that kind of
almost wraps us up but but guy we're
intercepting setember now we what's that
fall that's fall Now isn't it first the
first week of fall so August really was
pretty good for AI news around around a
number of startups making various
announcements of those announcements
anything catch your eye yeah we had a
bit of a a a flurry of funding
announcements in the AI Dev space
specifically right now you saw cursor
which is an AI focused IDE and more
announced a $60 million round we saw
codium with an E which is different than
codium AI that we had on it a very kind
of unfortunate reality I think for both
both codium companies it's not like you
just name your company codium and you
say oh I think many people will do that
anyways it is what it is so codium with
an E has raised a $150 million round at
a $1.25 billion post and maybe a bit
more interesting beyond the sort of the
VC hype maybe or like frenzy around this
domain not to say that it's overhyped
it's just but there's definitely a lot
of hype is the is that they published
that they have 700,000 active users I
don't know what active means here is
this like from the beginning or not even
if we assume 700,000 users that have
used the product at least once that's
substantial and over a th000 customers
and again I don't know if it's an
individual developer and I guess the
last one that that maybe sorted by by
size here is Magic Dev which is more of
a model company they're somewhat
secretive so I don't know everything
around it but they raised $320 million
and they claim that they effectively can
achieve a 100 million token context
window for code related things through
some smart summarization or or something
of that that nature and first of all
reinforces the point that there are many
different smart companies that are
trying to get Cod generation to work
better in many different ways definitely
reinforces the point on on dollars
flowing into this world to try this out
which is which is cool and I guess it
shows that it's not a co-pilot only
World which which is exciting because I
think I'm at fault of that as well which
is it's EAS hey AI Dev tool which one
would you name and I think there's like
a strong bias to towards co-pilot but
I'm happy to see a bunch of these
companies get some pretty substantial
Traction in adoption and I think that
would lead us to a better Dev tooling
ecosystem I had a look at some of the
co-pilot stats from just before this
session and actually there's not many
numbers apart from the Bigg bigger
announcement a while back which people
have maybe heard from Satia 40% of
github's growth this year came from from
co-pilot and and the lakes yeah
absolutely and open source developer
platforms now reached two billion run
rate cop has over 77,000 organizations
which are adopting 180% increase from
previous year so yeah slightly different
order but they're certainly not alone in
this space comparable numbers and growth
from other companies which is great to
see I think co-pilot is doing a great
job and GitHub and Microsoft
commercially are doing a great job kind
of bunding in and making it available to
many people and I think they're helping
the ecosystem in that they're
driving familiarity and trust and maybe
getting people to find out what they do
and what they don't like about copilot
which opens the door to now for a new
vendor to come and say hey here's a pain
because it's very hard when you build
tools when you build a startup a
disruptive entity you're disrupting some
pain you need to go to someone and say
hey I know you're doing this thing and
it you you really want to do it but this
aspect of it really annoys you and
you're building those out and when it's
a totally brand new practice yeah I know
you've been using these AI coding
assistants for all this time and aren't
you annoyed that when really the oldest
time is I've been using them for five
minutes it's hard to disrupt and so to
an extent they are establishing them
establishing themselves as an incumbent
as the starting point which on one hand
gives them some ability to reach many
users and on the other hand identifies
there's definitely a lot of magnifying
glasses on all the things that they're
not doing correctly and a whole bunch of
startups trying to address those in more
or less systematic ways yeah we'll see
what happens in the next few months as
well we'll we'll talk about anything
that we find interesting in the news as
well and I and I would say I guess if I
were a betting man but also I know of a
couple of them I think September and
October will have their own share of
exciting AI Dev tool announcements yeah
excellent we've got a few more sessions
great sessions coming up including one
that I just listened to actually for
next week so I'm looking forward with
that one Tamar the chief product officer
of glean so yeah very interesting
session which we'll be releasing next
week and many more for the rest of the
month so indeed indeed stay tuned for
other sessions coming up later this
month indeed in the meantime thanks all
for listening and uh tune in to the next
session see you
[Applause]
there thanks for tuning in join us next
time on the AI native Dev brought to you
by Tesla
[Music]